♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSICAL STING) ♪
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
(CLOCK TICKING RAPIDLY)
NEWS ANCHOR: (OVER TV)
Tonight, a 60 Minutes exclusive.
Ten years ago,
no one on Earth was aware
we were already
under the protection
of someone
calling himself Green Lantern.
Then, without warning,
he made himself known,
dramatically stopping a meteor
from devastating Victoria Falls.
Or, at least,
he made himself partially known.
Here now, we bring you
the first ever heart-to-heart
with a superhero.
Are you nervous?
GREEN LANTERN:
I don't get nervous.
- Part of the job description.
- NEWS ANCHOR: Of course.
GREEN LANTERN: Excited.
In that case, who are you?
- I'm Hal Jordan.
- (TV CLICKS OFF)
Damn it, Marcus!
You're gonna
get us all in trouble.
Just watch the window!
(TV CLICKS ON)
NEWS ANCHOR: So,
what do you want the world
to know about you?
HAL JORDAN:
I'm an Air Force veteran.
I'm a former test pilot.
And really...
just that I'm a regular person.
Like you.
NEWS ANCHOR:
Except that you're also
- Earth's first Green Lantern.
- ♪ (INTRIGUING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
HAL: (CHUCKLING)
There is that, too.
NEWS ANCHOR: In many ways,
Hal Jordan was born for the role
he would eventually play.
His father
was a decorated test pilot
who died tragically in a crash
when Hal was just eight.
Hal continued to follow
in his father's footsteps...
- (GASPS)
Shit, shit, shit! He's home!
- (NEWS ANCHOR TALKING ON TV)
AARON STEWART: Damn it!
Come on, John, turn the TV off!
- HAL:
Well, I'm the only one here.
- ♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
But we're like beat cops.
- Only each one of us...
- MARCUS: Turn it off!
- ...has a chunk of the galaxy.
- (JOHN STEWART JUNIOR SHUSHES)
NEWS ANCHOR: And how are you
chosen for this chunk?
- Is there a test?
- AARON: John!
- Come on, turn the TV off!
- It's only one question.
MARCUS STEWART:
(SIGHS) We're so dead.
"Are you afraid?"
And you said no.
I did.
Every kid's worst fear
is losing a parent.
Once that happens...
there is nothing
to fear anymore.
(KEYS JINGLING)
(DOOR UNLOCKING, OPENING)
♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
(DOOR CREAKING, CLOSING)
♪ (LOW TENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
So you gonna tell me
his real name?
Hal something.
Hal?
JOHN: Yes, sir.
- (FINGERS SNAP)
- Outside. Now.
♪ (BROODING
STRING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(KEYS JINGLING)
(GUN CLICKS)
Are you afraid?
No, sir!
♪ (MUSIC INTENSIFIES) ♪
♪ (TENDER STRING
MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
♪ (BROODING
STRING MUSIC RESUMES) ♪
Let's go get a burger.
- (PUNCHING BAG THUMPING)
- (CHAIN RATTLING)
♪ (MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
(EXHALING SHARPLY)
(GRUNTING SOFTLY)
(WATCH ALARM BEEPING)
(QUIETLY) Shit.
♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSICAL STING) ♪
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
(DISTANT CHATTER)
♪ ("BOOGIE SHOES" BY KC
AND THE SUNSHINE BAND
PLAYING OVER RADIO) ♪
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (CAR ENGINE REVVING)
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
♪ I can't wait
'Til I see you again ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Ah-ha, ah-ha ♪
♪ I wanna put on... ♪
I'm late.
Yes, sir.
You're not gonna say anything?
- (SCOFFS)
- ♪ My, my, my, my
My boogie shoes ♪
♪ Just to boogie with you ♪
♪ Ah-ha ♪
♪ I want do it
'Til the sun comes up... ♪
- (ENGINE REVVING)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
♪ I want to do it
'Til I can't get enough... ♪
HAL: You sure you're not mad?
- JOHN: No, sir.
- HAL: Me, I'd be pissed off.
Disappearing for two weeks,
no explanation,
show up hungover, and late.
Come on,
you gotta be a little angry.
JOHN: No, sir.
Mildly perturbed?
No, sir.
How come it is
every time you say "sir,"
it sounds more
and more like, "Fuck you"?
I have no idea.
Sir.
♪ ("BOOGIE SHOES" CONTINUES) ♪
You must be wondering
where I was?
- You ever heard of Pharon 4?
- Well, we're in training.
We haven't gone off-planet yet.
Yeah, yeah, that's right.
It's a shithole of a planet
that was on the verge
of civil war.
The point is, if I'm hungover,
it's only because
I was celebrating the new peace.
JOHN: So, how'd you manage it?
A little bit of diplomacy,
a little punching,
you know the drill.
Actually, I don't, sir.
That's the point.
Well, you got all the time
in the world.
JOHN: With all due respect,
we've been doing this, what,
two months?
And I haven't even
worn the ring yet.
Don't get hung up
on the jewelry, Junior.
You'll wear it
when it chooses you.
I thought the point was
that the Guardians chose me.
- That's all.
- The big blue bosses
may think that you're hot shit,
but you're just a fucking
substitute teacher, Junior.
You're not ready to get up
in front of the class
until the ring says you are.
♪ ("GET DOWN TONIGHT" BY KC
AND THE SUNSHINE BAND PLAYING) ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Do a little dance
Make a little love... ♪
HAL: Here.
You wanna take it?
Is that a test?
There's a taco stand up the road
about three miles.
I'll meet you there.
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Do a little dance
Make a little love ♪
♪ Get down tonight
Get down tonight ♪
♪ Hey! ♪
♪ Do a little dance... ♪
- (RING WHIRRING)
- ♪ (SONG CUTS OFF) ♪
(WIND BLOWING SOFTLY)
♪ (FAINT EERIE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
- (CABLES HUMMING)
- (EAGLE SCREECHING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
(DIAL TONE RINGING)
- JOHN STEWART SENIOR: Hello?
- JOHN: Dad, he tried to kill me.
We was on our way
to a flying lesson, and he--
Jordan just tried
to fucking kill me.
JOHN SENIOR: He can't kill you.
He's just trying
to put you on tilt.
I'm not on fucking tilt.
JOHN SENIOR:
Then he's testing you.
They're allowed
to have tantrums.
We're not. So breathe in,
button down, and bottle up.
You need to be cool.
Can you be cool, son?
- Yes, sir. I can be cool.
- JOHN SENIOR: Good.
- You want this, right?
- Of course, I want this.
JOHN SENIOR:
Just stay the course
and this job is yours.
Yeah, well...
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
(RING PULSING)
(RING WARBLING)
Shit.
Am I dead?
- What?
- You're wearing my ring.
Is that supposed to be funny?
Hey, did I do something
to piss you off?
'Cause if I did, I'm sorry.
You? Hal Jordan? Sorry?
- (CHUCKLES)
- That's right.
I must have a concussion.
Wait a sec. Wait a sec.
Let's start at the beginning.
Who are you
and why are you wearing my ring?
I'm John Stewart, your trainee.
Lanterns don't have trainees
from their own sector.
JOHN: They do now.
What year is it?
2016.
Holy...
You want to tell me
what you think is going on?
I'm a backup
of Hal Jordan's consciousness,
combined with the sentience
of the ring,
I'm here
to give myself a message.
So you are Hal?
No. Yes. Mostly. Ish.
(HESITATES) Well, it's like when
you store yourself in the cloud,
only every once in a while,
when you're needed
in the real world, you...
Lanterns, they're required
to be uploaded weekly,
for posterity's sake, in case
something happens to us.
I should have taught you this.
I thought I was training you.
Yeah, I thought so, too.
When were you last backed up?
Evidently, ten years ago.
Listen, I need to find myself.
- Where am I?
- Oh, you're three miles
up the street eating tacos.
Oh, good.
You can fly us there, then.
I-- I haven't...
taught you how to fly yet,
have I?
JOHN: I'll tell you what.
You tell me
what you want me to tell you.
Do I trust you?
I mean, you know, we, uh...
You know, we get along?
We get along great.
There's hail
in Rushville, Nebraska.
That's it?
Well, I'll know what I mean.
Hm.
(RING WARBLING)
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
- (CUSTOMERS CLAMORING)
- CUSTOMER 1: Hey,
it's Green Lantern!
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
- CUSTOMER 2:
You're a legend, man.
- CUSTOMER 3: Thank you.
CUSTOMER 4:
Yes, I want a selfie!
- OWNER: Let the man breathe!
- (CHUCKLES)
OWNER: It's not a petting zoo.
Come on.
I'll bring your food
to your table, Mr. Jordan.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
- OWNER: All right, guys.
- HAL: Thanks very much. Thanks.
♪ (LATIN MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS) ♪
Um, um, I'm...
Do you think that my daughter
could maybe...
- Absolutely. Come here.
Come on. Come here.
- (MOTHER LAUGHING)
(QUIETLY) There we go.
- (SIGHS)
- HAL: Okay.
- Thank you.
- HAL: You're very welcome.
- She misses the suit.
- I didn't say that.
Tell your mom I still wear it
on special occasions.
- (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
- (QUIETLY) Yeah.
(FAINT CHATTER)
I could have fucking died.
You want me to train you,
I'm training you.
How'd you save yourself?
What'd you make with the ring?
Bubble wrap.
- Oh, you're a genius.
- JOHN: Yeah.
OWNER: Dessert's on the house.
HAL: Well, thank you very much.
Can I ask why only
on special occasions?
It's like when you're young
and eager
and you like to prove yourself,
so you wear a tie
so people
will take you seriously.
But when you get older
and wiser...
you realize ties
are a pain in the ass.
(SOFTLY) Ah.
- Good one.
- HAL: Hmm.
Yeah. Good one.
Give me my ring.
You sent yourself a message,
by the way.
- What are you talking about?
- JOHN: The ring.
Your backup consciousness.
You were a lot nicer
ten years ago.
What did I say?
There's hail
in Rushville, Nebraska.
Pay the check.
♪ ("NO FUN"
BY THE STOOGES PLAYING) ♪
(EXCITED CHATTER, CHEERING)
- ♪ No fun, my babe ♪
- (SOFTLY) Motherfucker.
♪ No fun ♪
♪ No fun, my babe ♪
♪ No fun to hang around ♪
♪ Feelin' that same old way ♪
♪ Freaked out ♪
- ♪ For another day ♪
- ♪ (SONG CONCLUDES) ♪
- (DISTANT SIRENS BLARING)
- (HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Sorry, no one's allowed in.
Really? It seems like
the whole town's in there.
DEPUTY LOPEZ: Oh, come on.
That's enough, don't you think?
John Stewart.
I'm with Hal Jordan.
We're partners.
I thought there was only
one Green Lantern.
Well, technically,
I'm in training.
Hmm, so like a sidekick?
Why don't you
just make the call?
Hey, boss. (SIGHS)
There's another one.
(RADIO CRACKLES)
SHERIFF: (OVER RADIO)
You fucking kidding me?
Tell him to stay
on the fucking sidelines
with that other
fucking shithead.
(SHERIFF CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY)
- DEPUTY LOPEZ: Yes, ma'am.
- (RADIO CHIRPS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER CONTINUES)
What's the word?
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
Stay off the field.
- (DISTANT SIRENS BLARING)
- (HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
(DISTANT CLAMOR)
JOHN: You ditched me.
I was testing you,
seeing if you had it in you
to get yourself here
on your own.
JOHN:
You've been here six hours,
so why are they still processing
the scene?
Uh, emergency services
from two different counties.
They're interviewing witnesses,
escorting them out 10 at a time.
It's a decidedly
small-town pace.
I don't get it.
You flew all the way here
just to ride the bench.
The answer to that mystery
is heading right to you.
Hey, Sheriff, uh, uh...
Kane. It-- Uh, John Stewart.
KERRY KANE: Kerry.
- John. Training under Hal.
- (SCOFFS) What an honor.
'Cause it was certainly
an honor to meet him
when he arrived.
- You don't have jurisdiction.
- She's about to tell you
we don't have jurisdiction.
- You don't.
- I will.
I can't do this again.
Look, you're a big shot. Noted.
But your jurisdiction
only covers
extraterrestrial events.
This... This is pretty much
the definition of terrestrial.
These victims are going
to end up being aliens.
- Based on what?
- HAL: I have a feeling.
(GASPS) He has a feeling.
I have a very strong feeling.
Well, then, by all means,
the scene is yours.
Well, it seems kind of mellow
for a mass shooting,
don't you think?
They're in shock.
Or nobody knows the victims.
Does anybody seem extra upset
to you down there?
You see anybody standing
with the bodies?
Say it with me now.
Aliens.
Look, I know you think
you're helping,
but you need to trust me.
These people are my friends.
They're my neighbors.
They understand your job.
They know we're not alone.
There's a difference
between hearing that on CNN
and seeing it up close.
If it ends up being the case,
we'll deal with it.
But until then, I'm trying
to keep the scene calm.
So if you could do me a favor,
keep away from the news vans.
It was nice to meet you.
Now, if you'll both kindly stay
the fuck out of my way.
She's something incredible,
isn't she?
I think she hates your guts.
Yeah, but it's the way
she hates them.
- (CLAMOR CONTINUES)
- (HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
JOHN: So, what's going on here?
Well, if I'm not mistaken--
Why don't you tell me?
♪ (BROODING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Looks to me like
Rushville scored
a game-winning field goal.
- (WHISTLE BLOWING)
- (FANS CHEERING)
JOHN: Kicking block
is still out there.
Fence is broken.
My guess is
home fans rushed the field.
This being a rivalry,
a few visitor fans
wander onto the field.
This being Nebraska,
more than a few are carrying.
(GUN SHOTS ECHOING)
JOHN: You got four dead,
all in visitor sweatshirts.
And still none of this explains
why you think it has anything
to do with aliens.
♪ (TENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
You know,
I've been doing this job
since you were a baby.
I'm the only person
on this whole goddamn planet
that's ever done this job.
I say I got a fucking feeling,
I got a fucking feeling, Junior.
"There's hail
in Rushville, Nebraska."
You've been monitoring
this exact spot.
"Hail" obviously means aliens.
Christ, they even sound
the fucking same.
So we both know this is more
than just a feeling.
- Do we?
- Yeah, we do.
Here's all you need to know.
- JOHN: Hmm.
- This is my job.
As long as I'm alive,
that ain't changing.
And I don't plan on dying
anytime soon,
so why don't you do yourself
a big favor
and take a nice long,
deep breath, Junior?
(SCOFFS)
♪ (UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(SOFTLY) Fuck.
I think one of them
is still here.
HAL: Yeah, the one
in the short-sleeved shirt.
Been clocking him
since I got here,
trying to figure out
why he didn't bolt,
what he still wants here.
You told the sheriff?
Of course not.
But it's her crime scene.
That's how you'd play this
if you had the ring?
Yeah.
I respect the chain of command.
Well, by all means,
go respect it.
♪ (BROODING
STRING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Would you excuse me?
- Hey, shithead.
- ♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
What part of stay the fuck away,
was confusing?
There's something
you need to see.
If you're about to tell me
about the redneck
in the short sleeves
who ditched
his only warm clothes
so we wouldn't put him
with the other victims,
I'm trying to make sure
he doesn't get spooked
and start shooting the place up
like his dead friends.
I just fucked up, didn't I?
I suspect you did.
♪ (INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Fuck.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
(DOOR CLOSES)
♪ (MUSIC BUILDS) ♪
♪ (MUSIC INTENSIFIES) ♪
- (GROANS)
- ♪ (MUSIC CUTS OFF) ♪
(LOUD THUD)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(KERRY GRUNTING)
- (EXHALES)
- (PANTS)
(HANDCUFFS RATTLING)
(PANTS) You got him?
- (GROANS)
- Sure.
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
- I need to interrogate him.
- Like fucking hell you do.
- (JOHN PANTING)
- (CAR ENGINE STARTING)
Hi.
- JOHN: Yeah.
- You thirsty?
- (RING WARBLING)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(JUKEBOX WHIRRING)
♪ ("BRAND NEW KEY"
BY MELANIE PLAYING) ♪
HAL: Howdy, fellas.
♪ I rode my bicycle
Past your window last night... ♪
Hey, can I have another,
another, and another?
BARTENDER: Sure thing.
Did you just use that ring
to counterfeit money?
No. I manifested money
with the power of my will.
Oh, wow.
But you couldn't manifest
something
for the guy I was chasing.
Got it.
This ring is a dangerous weapon.
When and if to use it,
that's the whole ball game,
Junior.
Tell me how you got it,
the ring.
You know how I got it.
JOHN: Yeah, but I mean,
what I know can't be true, right?
Well, I got it
the old-fashioned way.
I sure as hell
didn't interview for it.
Oh, well, shit,
maybe you should have.
I mean, power like that,
shouldn't you have
to work for it,
excel, prove yourself,
instead of just
getting randomly selected?
Why do you give a shit
how I got my ring?
Because I think that's why
we're in goddamn Nebraska.
I was a couple years
into being a test pilot.
You know, middle of the night,
I'm sleeping off
about nine too many,
still had my boots and jeans on.
All of a sudden,
my room starts to vibrate.
I open my eyes,
and I'm in a big fucking bubble.
A big fucking green bubble.
This green bubble floats me up
out of bed.
Next thing I know,
there's a voice
running through my entire body,
bones, teeth, heart,
the whole deal.
And it says to me...
"Are you afraid?"
I say, "No.
I'm not afraid."
Wham!
Yanks me out the window
across the sky
like a fish getting reeled in.
Couple hundred miles
in about ten seconds.
(CHUCKLES) I fly fighter jets.
I have an excellent sense
of airspeed and bearing.
That's how I know exactly
where that green bubble
set me down.
Nebraska.
HAL: Not more than 20 miles
from where we sit right now.
Which is middle
of fucking nowhere.
Thus, an excellent place
to crash a spaceship.
There he was.
Right in front of me.
The pilot.
Bonafide fucking alien.
Pink and bald, coughing up
glow-in-the-dark blood.
- It was pretty fucking intense.
- ♪ (SONG CONCLUDES) ♪
(JUKEBOX CLICKING)
♪ ("BRAND NEW KEY"
BY MELANIE PLAYING FROM START) ♪
Hey, you think you're funny?
HAL: So Pinko starts talking.
And it comes out
all clicks and gurgles.
He's dying.
And he gives me his ring.
This ring.
And when I put it on,
I can understand
every fucking word he says.
"My name is Abin Sur,
responsible for maintaining
the peace and sovereignty
of Sector 2814.
And this responsibility
is now yours,
as the ring has chosen you
to be my successor."
Now, fuck, did I know
what sovereignty meant?
Hell no, I didn't.
And then he said two more words,
his last words.
And he kind of whispered 'em,
so I'm never really sure
whether he said "Good luck"
or "Ah, fuck."
Anyway, it turns out
Earth's way off grid,
out of their jurisdiction.
Galactic fucking backwater.
A human getting a ring,
isn't it a fucking fluke?
The big, blue bosses,
they'd never wanted any Lantern
coming near
our little shithole planet.
And that's why my gut
always told me
that crash was no accident.
When it says
there's a shitstorm en route,
I make sure there's a lookout
to tell me
when it's fucking coming.
The Halogram.
Halogram.
(CHUCKLES) That's clever.
Hmm. Thank you.
- Hm. It's not that clever.
- ♪ (SONG CONCLUDES) ♪
- (JUKEBOX CLICKING)
- ♪ ("BRAND NEW KEY"
BY MELANIE PLAYING FROM START) ♪
PATRON: Hey, Jordan! Ass-face!
You ignoring me?
So help me God, if that song
plays one more time,
I'm gonna put you
inside that fucking jukebox!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(QUIETLY) Hal,
I think he's talking to you.
Yeah, I hear him.
JOHN: You want to fight?
You want to go to jail.
You want to go to jail
so you can talk to that guy
that Mrs. Sheriff
doesn't want you to talk to.
Not guy.
- Alien.
- This is a stupid plan.
- HAL: I've had stupider.
- That I do not doubt.
All right. Here we go.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
Look, uh, it's gonna look
like they're really kicking
the shit out of me,
so you're gonna be tempted
to jump in,
but I need you
to stay right here.
Will do. You got it.
Thanks.
♪ I don't go too fast
But I go pretty far... ♪
Hey, fellas.
Tell me something, would you?
What the fuck is your problem
with roller skates?
PATRON: Look, pretty boy.
Show me what you got.
HAL: Oh, my.
You look like my sister.
God bless ya. Now what?
PATRON: What the fuck
are you talking about?
STRANGER: You gonna say yes?
He didn't get down on one knee,
but a ring's a ring.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
No, I don't think he wants me
to have this ring.
Ever.
- But he gave it to you.
- I reckon he's testing me.
STRANGER: Testing you how?
♪ I got a brand-new pair
Of roller skates... ♪
- (RING CLINKS)
- Who gives a shit?
- (STRANGER CHUCKLES)
- HAL: Come on, bring it on.
What are you drinking, stranger?
JOHN: Coke.
- STRANGER: Coke and what?
- Coke and Coke.
Don't tell me
you're a teetotaler.
No, I'm just...
- I'm just on the job.
- (INDISTINCT CLAMOR)
Being a space cop.
Who told you I was a space cop?
I mean, your partner is one.
Figured you are too.
Uh, he's not my partner.
I'm his trainee.
(GROANS)
STRANGER:
How many trainees does he have?
- Just me.
- Why'd he pick you?
JOHN: He didn't. Our bosses did.
Space cops have bosses?
(CHUCKLES)
♪ ("COMING HOME"
BY LEON BRIDGES PLAYING) ♪
Come on, ev-- everybody's
got bosses, you know?
(INDISTINCT CLAMOR)
(HAL GRUNTING)
STRANGER:
So, once you're trained,
then you're an official
space cop too?
- Well, the way it works is...
- STRANGER: Mm-hmm.
...Earth has one Lantern.
So I'm just being trained
in case
anything happens to Jordan.
So you're the backup
quarterback.
I'm patient.
No, you're not.
KERRY: All right, idiots.
Break it up!
(INDISTINCT CLAMOR)
- OFFICER: Get out!
- KERRY: Do I gotta call
your mom again?
Get out of here. Now!
(GROANS, GRUNTS)
♪ Wanna be around, girl ♪
♪ Ooh, wanna be around... ♪
OFFICER: Let's go.
Let's go, sweetness.
KERRY: Get him out of here!
OFFICER: Yeah, yeah.
Nice talking to you, stranger.
I'm John.
Walk me to my truck, John?
♪ By myself
I don't want nobody else ♪
♪ The world leaves
A bitter taste ♪
♪ In my mouth, girl ♪
♪ You're the only one
That I want ♪
- ♪ Wanna be around ♪
- (STRANGER MOANS)
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Wanna be around, girl... ♪
You gonna give me a lecture?
(SOFTLY) No.
I'm gonna give you a light.
- ♪ Ooh, wanna be around ♪
- (RING WARBLING)
- ♪ Baby, baby ♪
- ♪ (SONG CONCLUDES) ♪
KERRY: Because no comment
means no comment.
(LOCK BUZZING)
KERRY: I'm not gonna talk
about an active investigation,
- you know that.
- (TELEPHONE RINGING)
KERRY: Okay.
- Good.
- (DOOR CLOSES)
Tell Barb I said hey.
(PHONE CLATTERS)
I take it you're here
to bail out your buddy?
Want some coffee?
JOHN: I am,
and, um, no thank you.
He's in a bit of a mood
because I locked him
in our broom closet.
(COFFEE CARAFE THUDS)
It's almost as if
he wanted to get arrested...
- (DOOR OPENS)
- ...so I'd throw him in jail
next to the suspect
- I told him he couldn't talk to.
- (DOOR CLOSES)
JOHN: I did tell him
it was a stupid plan.
- (MUG THUDS)
- You should have
told him louder.
Well, listen, may I take
my stupid friend home?
Not until he's arraigned.
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
Really?
JUDGE: ...and eight counts
of aggravated assault
and resisting arrest.
How does the defendant plead?
HAL: With all due respect,
Your Honor, come on.
"Come on"?
Look, I'm just trying
to question a suspect
in the course
of a very serious investigation,
- which I--
- JUDGE: Ah, an investigation.
Am I to understand, sir,
that you are
a law enforcement official?
And if so, could you kindly
state for the record
which agency you represent?
I'm Green Lantern.
JUDGE:
I didn't ask who you were.
I asked which bureau
you are an agent of.
I'm Green Lantern,
and I'm an agent of...
the Green Lantern... s.
Look, I introduced myself
to Lady Justice back here
when I got to the crime scene,
and I deferred
to her jurisdiction.
Is that accurate, Sheriff?
Yeah, but the deference
was pretty cheeky, Your Honor.
- You cheeky, Mr. Jordan?
- (DOOR OPENS)
- WILLIAM "BILLY" MACON:
Yeah, don't-- don't answer that.
- (DOOR CLOSES)
(CLEARS THROAT) William Macon
for the defense, Your Honor.
- Sorry I'm late.
- JUDGE: Mr. Macon.
The defendant has chosen
to represent himself.
That's only because
he doesn't understand
he's being made an example of,
which, Your Honor,
is absurd given Mr. Jordan
is a hero.
Granted, he hasn't, uh,
formally retained my--
- You're hired. He's hired.
- Fantastic.
The defense enters a plea
of not guilty
and asks Your Honor
to set reasonable bail,
even understanding Mr. Jordan
is... technically a flight risk.
Because...
he can fly.
- (QUIETLY) Who is this guy?
- (SCOFFS)
My husband.
JUDGE: I'm setting bail
at 100,000 dollars.
- Oh, come on.
- JUDGE: Two hundred thousand.
Now you know the price
of each "come on," Mr. Jordan.
- Shall we try another?
- No, that's understood.
And thank you, Your Honor.
My father will have the check
to your clerk by lunch.
All right, then.
Mr. Jordan, don't leave town.
- We're adjourned.
- (GAVEL THUDS)
- Uh, thanks for the save.
- Oh, truly an honor.
But I tend to find
that strangers who give me
a couple
hundred thousand dollars,
no strings attached,
usually turn out to be bad guys.
Uh, but there are
strings attached, Mr. Jordan.
My father would love
to have supper
with you this evening.
Um, he's a huge fan,
and someone I think
you'll find like-minded.
What are you doing, Billy?
Uh, I was just
inviting Mr. Jordan
up to the ranch tonight, honey.
They're married.
Course, they are.
Small town, everyone's related.
Oh.
I'd be offended if that wasn't
absolutely true. (CHUCKLES)
Billy Macon, you must be John.
- Yes, sir.
- BILLY: You like barbecue?
(SCOFFS) Junior here's a vegan.
He doesn't believe in anything
that causes enjoyment.
But we'd love to come to supper.
Yeah, well, only if it's okay
with the sheriff.
The more the merrier.
(CHUCKLES)
HAL: Hmm.
♪ (LOW BROODING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(GATE UNLOCKING)
- ♪ (MUSIC BUILDING) ♪
- (INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(GUNSHOTS)
Militia?
Walks like a duck,
shoots an AR-15 like a duck,
blah, blah, blah, duck.
(HORSE NEIGHS)
(HORSE CHUFFS)
♪ (MUSIC INTENSIFYING) ♪
♪ (MUSIC FALLS) ♪
- ♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
- BILLY: Evening.
- So glad you could make it.
- JOHN: How you doing?
Uh, this is our boy, Noah.
JOHN: All right.
How you doing, Noah?
Noah, this is Mr. Stewart
and Mr. Jordan.
HAL: Noah.
Offense or defense?
Wherever they need me, sir.
HAL: Team player. Good man.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(SIGHS) Oh, sorry.
Uh, I got to take this.
Uh, Dad's waiting in the kitchen
for you gentlemen.
Noah, come with me
and help Grandma set up.
Hey.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER OVER PHONE)
BILLY: Yeah.
Oh.
How about a beer?
God, yes.
HAL: Oh, here.
(RING WARBLING)
(BOTTLE CAP CLINKS)
(BLOWS)
My father-in-law's
got paper on you
and you haven't even
met him yet.
He's not a man you want to owe.
Hm. Sounds like a woman in debt.
It's not too late.
You can just fly on home,
spare yourself the moment
not too long from now
when you wish
you'd never come to this place.
No.
- ♪ (CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- (DOOR OPENS)
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- Well... (CHUCKLES)
Exciting enough Hal Jordan just
walked into my kitchen,
but with a bag of beer?
I'm truly blessed.
Least I can do. This is John.
John, Will Macon.
I'd shake, but my hands
are all gunky with meat.
Word on the street
is you don't partake.
Ordered you up some tofu steaks.
- Hope that'll do you.
- Oh, that's very kind.
I appreciate it.
And I appreciate
your service, sir.
Marine sniper.
Color me impressed.
- Oh, looked me up.
- Mm.
WILLIAM "WILL" MACON:
You didn't look me up?
(CLEAVER THUDS)
Jesus.
Walking into unknown territory,
even with a weapon
of mass destruction
on your finger,
that's either trust
or arrogance.
Well, he's trust. I'm arrogance.
I don't trust anybody.
WILL: Man after my own heart.
You got a nice place here, Will.
Yeah, it is, isn't it?
Alas, not mine.
I'm just a caretaker.
Mind me asking
who you caretake it for?
I don't mind at all.
Regrettably, my NDA
restricts me from discussing
or IDing my employer.
Because of the government.
I'm sorry?
The government.
I'm guessing the government,
they're probably
watching your boss,
biding their time
before they raid this compound,
take his guns and rights away.
You think we bailed you out
so we could enlist you
in some whackadoo war
with the feds?
Well, why else would you
bail me out?
Because of the goddamn aliens, son.
Why the fuck else?
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
Man, the whole world flipped out
when you first came
on the scene.
Makes sense,
seeing what you can do.
But it kind of buried the lede.
There are thousands
of planets out there
with intelligent life.
And here we sit,
low-hanging fruit of the galaxy,
just waiting to get gobbled up.
This land we're on right now,
it was Kiowa, then Sioux,
but across the ocean
boats were coming.
Anyways, as someone
who's spent time in the galaxy,
it's a pretty
peaceful place out there.
Well, what do they need
space cops for?
♪ (TENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Look, I'm not some
isolationist crackpot
with his head in the sand,
but I am a student of history.
Colonization is ugly
from any angle,
but I tell you,
it is particularly bleak
if you're the one
getting colonized.
This all, call it
an ounce of prevention.
Seems like a bit more
than an ounce.
WILL: My point is,
I believe the gentleman
cooling his heels
in the sheriff's pokey,
he's part of an advanced team.
And I'd ask you
what your reason to believe is,
but I'm guessing
it's covered by your NDA.
My daughter-in-law says
you're not that bright.
HAL: Your daughter-in-law's
what's holding me up
from talking to that fella.
WILL: All right.
I can clear that brush.
In exchange for?
Let's eat.
♪ (TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
♪ (MUSIC FADING) ♪
(HORSE NEIGHING)
JOHN: You're aiming.
Sorry, sir?
Don't aim.
Just imagine it going through.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Try again.
Hey, don't-- don't force it.
Just imagine.
- (NOAH MACON CHUCKLES)
- JOHN: Hey!
What'd I say?
What'd I just say?
That was great.
NOAH:
How'd you know that?
So, my dad used to shoot apples
off my head.
Grandma!
Grandma, I got one through!
STRANGER: Show me, sweetheart.
You live here?
Mm-hmm.
Zoe Macon.
Now you have my name.
Come on, sweetheart.
Let's go find everyone.
- NOAH: All right.
- ZOE: Come on.
- (DOG BARKING)
- (HORSE NEIGHING)
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
WILL: Well,
we drank all your beer,
but put together
some leftovers for you.
- Much obliged.
- And I talked to Kerry.
Since you and I have
common interests,
she's willing to let you chat
with the suspect
- first thing in the morning.
- (CAR DOOR OPENS)
HAL: Well...
You know,
that's the thing, Will.
I don't know
what your interests are.
Two of my boys
almost got killed last night
in a shootout with men
no one's ever seen before.
How about we both want
to protect the planet
from anybody not born on it?
Hope I didn't mess up
your tofu, soldier.
No, sir.
It was delicious.
Good.
Nothing better than eating off
another man's grill.
Good night, gentlemen.
- (FOOTSTEPS DEPARTING)
- (WILL WHISTLING)
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
Hey.
What was that all about?
(VEHICLE DEPARTING)
I might have slept
with his wife.
Might have?
I definitely slept
with his wife.
♪ (BROODING
STRING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
And he knows?
(QUIETLY) Apparently.
Jesus Christ,
we've only been here 24 hours.
I'm impressed.
♪ (MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
KERRY: We said 9:00.
HAL: What time is it?
Not 9:00.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
His name's Waylon Sanders.
Commercial-licensed
truck driver. Called his boss,
says he's worked for him
almost five years now.
Mm-hmm.
Aliens are good at getting IDs
and paying people
to lie for them.
He's just a dipshit
from Kimball.
They took X-rays at the hospital
for his busted nose.
All organs accounted for.
No hidden antennas.
The plural
for antenna is antennae.
- What's the plural for eat shit?
- (CHUCKLES)
Junior, tell the sheriff here
how many species currently
have the technology
to pass as human.
Fourteen.
MRIs, X-rays, blood work.
Nothing down here
can tell the difference.
- So you can't prove it.
- I can make him confess.
If you lay a finger on him,
you're back
in front of the judge.
That includes whacking him
with giant green phone books
or whatever you magic up
from your conjuring ring.
I wouldn't dare.
KERRY: Ten minutes.
- HAL: I only need five.
- (LOCK BUZZES)
- Am I'm coming in with you?
- HAL: You are not.
(DOOR OPENS)
- Alien my ass.
- (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
You know, we're all aliens.
Just depends which planet
you're standing on.
HAL:
Would you like a cup of coffee?
- No, thank you.
- HAL: All right.
Yeah, I imagine you just
want to phone home, or...
- get home, I bet.
- WAYLON SANDERS: Yes, sir.
And home is Kimball?
Well, I mean, I'm on the road
most of the year,
but Kimball's where
I hang my hat. Yes, sir.
(CHUCKLES) "Hang your hat."
What a delightful
human expression.
And, uh, well, if you're in town
for the big game,
it must be a big rivalry.
I mean, uh, Kimball's, what,
that's a two,
two-and-a-half-hour drive?
Yeah, sorry about that.
I just, you know, I--
I love football, though,
and, uh, it's the home team.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
I love football, too.
When did Nebraska win
its first national championship?
- Sorry?
- Uh...
You love football.
You're from Nebraska.
Huskers' first championship,
when was that?
- Yeah, it was 1970, Bob Devaney.
- That is correct.
How about their first
200-yard rusher?
Uh...
- Frank Solich?
- First Heisman winner?
- Johnny Rodgers.
- (CHUCKLES) That's it.
Where did Harry Potter
go to school?
Excuse me?
HAL: Harry Potter, boy wizard.
What was the name of the school?
(SOFTLY) I don't know.
HAL: It was a book.
I don't read a lot.
Well, you go
to the movies, don't you?
They only made,
like, 22 of them.
Oh, I watch a lot of football.
- HAL: That's the rub, isn't it?
- What?
Pretending to be someone
that you're not.
You learn all the specifics,
but you don't learn
what everyone else knows.
Uh... (EXHALES SHARPLY)
I don't-- I don't understand.
Who are you, exactly?
Hal Jordan, Green Lantern.
♪ (INTRIGUING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Charged by
the Guardians of the Universe
to protect Sector 2814
from
all extra-planetary threats.
And you, Waylon,
are one of them.
Good Christ, he really is
full of himself, isn't he?
Can't be easy,
having to learn
from someone you don't respect.
I do respect him.
- KERRY: Come on.
- JOHN: I do.
KERRY: Why?
(HAL CONTINUES
SPEAKING OVER SPEAKER)
I don't know. He's fearless.
If you care about people,
you know, husband,
wife, parent, kid,
then you're scared
of losing them.
First time he strutted up to me,
I could tell Jordan doesn't
care about anybody.
- And nobody cares about him.
- ♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
He's not fucking fearless.
He's lonely.
HAL: But--
But why did you stick around?
What were you looking for?
I mean, I get once I showed up,
you couldn't run.
You had to blend in.
But before that...
I just went to a high school
football game, man.
With the other Kimball fans
who are all dead now.
WAYLON: I don't know them, okay?
I told you, I-- I drive a truck.
HAL: Yeah, I'm sure
you can tell me a lot
about that truck,
but I bet you can't tell me
about the Boston Tea Party,
Kelly Clarkson,
Barack Obama, or Rup--
Barack Obama is the president
of the United States.
That's it?
As a rural Nebraskan,
that's the breadth
of your opinion
of Barack Hussein Obama?
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
He is the 44th president.
He followed George W. Bush.
There's some controversy
surrounding
his birth certificate.
Holy shit, you are an alien.
♪ (UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(SIGHS)
Let's say you're right.
Oh, fuck.
WAYLON:
Let's say, hypothetically,
that I'm not of this salty,
smelly world,
a visitor
who went to great trouble
to hide himself well
and learn the arcane rules
of pointless contests
involving balls
that somehow
captivate more attention
than the
deteriorating atmosphere
or the hunger
of its least fortunate people.
If I had gone to such lengths,
I would be here
for a very important purpose.
A purpose that required
great discretion and secrecy.
A purpose that would need
to be kept from the likes
of a galactic
peacekeeping organization
because it concerns
the exact opposite of peace.
That being war.
And as such,
if I were to fall into the hands
of such an organization,
I would be forced
to take drastic measures
to ensure that my purpose
was not revealed.
Hypothetically.
And hypothetically,
what might you have
to keep your mouth shut?
- A cyanide pill?
- You're thinking very small.
Then give it to me big.
I'd have
a biometric neutron device
woven into my skeleton.
I'd be able to activate it
with a thought.
Unless you let me walk out
that door right now.
He's bluffing, right?
HAL: You're not walking out
of here hypothetically
or otherwise.
And if you do blow yourself up,
I'm just gonna bubble up
and contain all that sunshine
with my ring
and walk out of here
without a scratch.
You've been here 48 hours.
Did you bring the lantern
to recharge your ring?
I have plenty of power.
Hmm. But for how much longer?
Yeah.
You should be asking yourself
if I'm capable of releasing
enough energy
to eradicate this entire town.
We talking or exploding?
Because it's almost lunchtime.
(HANDCUFFS RATTLE)
It almost seems like you...
want to die, Hal Jordan.
Does that not violate
your precious oath?
"In brightest day
and blackest night..."
- HAL: Don't.
- "...no evil
- shall escape my sight."
- Shut your mouth.
WAYLON: "Let those
who worship evil's might
- beware my power...
- I said don't.
(CHUCKLES)
...Green Lantern's light."
- (WAYLON GRUNTS)
- ♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
Harry Potter went to Hogwarts,
you ignorant alien fuck!
(WAYLON LAUGHS, SIGHS)
(BEEPING)
- Are you beeping?
- Should we go? We should go.
- No, it's too late.
- Why are you here?
WAYLON: Why else?
Vengeance.
(BEEPING INTENSIFIES)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(RING HUMMING)
(EXPLOSION ECHOING)
(SILENCE)
- (ALARMS BLARING)
- (INDISTINCT CLAMOR)
(KERRY GROANS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
(GLASS CRUNCHING)
Told you he was an alien.
(DISTANT SIRENS BLARING)
♪ (INTRIGUING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- ♪ (MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
- ♪ (BROODING VOCALIZATIONS) ♪
♪ (INTRIGUING MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
(DISTANT TRAIN HORN BLARING)
KERRY: Look at you.
You've barely aged.
Liar.
- How's Noah?
- (KERRY SIGHS)
Tall. He's on the team now.
Quarterback.
He any good?
KERRY: All-state.
That's good.
Anyone else know?
Just the groundskeeper.
All right.
♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(WIND HOWLING)
♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
♪ ("KNIEVEL"
BY SCUD MOUNTAIN BOYS PLAYING) ♪
♪ If I tried to leap the moon
Would you ever care? ♪
♪ Would you ever care? ♪
♪ And if I left the earth
Too soon ♪
♪ Would you ever dare? ♪
♪ It didn't take much living
To see ♪
♪ That I was bound
To leave the ground ♪
♪ It didn't take much living
To see ♪
♪ That I'm only free
When I'm flying ♪
♪ Flying ♪
♪ When I'm flying ♪
♪ Flying, I'm flying ♪
♪ Flying ♪
♪ (GUITAR SOLO PLAYING) ♪
♪ (SONG CONCLUDES) ♪